Hello friends, today I am going to
tell you about two wheeler policy. If
you have any two wheeler policy or
two wheeler bike, then how can you make an insurance claim.
Look, I have a
policy today and this policy is an ICICI
policy. Look, it is an ICICI policy.
I have an
ICICI policy.
First of all, you have to check your insurance whether it is
first party or
third party. If there is third party
insurance, then you cannot claim on the third party
and on the first party. There are
two types of insurance on the first party as well, one is a
package policy and the other is a zero
deposit. If it is a zero deposit policy, then
you get the deposit in it
and it always charges 10%, but it
is free on fiber and if any part
of the vehicle changes metal, then 10% will be charged on it.
Fiber is free. In zero policy also, in many
places, it happens that they charge on both fiber and metal.
This
benefits the company and the customer suffers a loss. So,
definitely keep this in mind and package  If you have a
policy, whether it is plastic or
metal, the money will be charged equally, 50% only,
50% will be borne by the customer and 50% will be borne by the insurance
company, it happens at many places,
keep this in mind that it is cashless, there is a cashless facility
for the customer, if you have
taken the car from any garage, if you claim at the same place then
you will get cashless
and if it is an Adar policy or if you get it
cleaned anywhere then they will not give you cashless,
for that you will have to submit a cancelled cheque
and
whatever money is there will come in your account
but you will have to pay the full amount there,
hence you cannot get this cashless facility everywhere, so
see this, I have
zero deposit, this is a zero deposit policy,
see this at ICICI, at this place it is
written zero deposition and on this itself if
only on damage is written here and
zero temperature is not written below, then it is
written in the place of on damage, then that is only a package policy,
if zero depression is added then
you have zero dep insurance and first of all
if you have a car  If you want to claim for this then the
documents that you will need are the
insurance of the vehicle, RC of the vehicle,
driving license of the owner and
Aadhar card and PAN card of the owner and if cashless
facility is available then there will be no need of cancelled cheque,
if cashless facility is not available
then you will have to use cancelled cheque, keep this thing in
mind and you will have to take these things with you,
if you have this policy then see,
download the claim form of this, it
is available on the net, you can go to any net
and see, there is a toll free number given on this,
see this
18266, you can call on this number and
whatever policy you have, the toll free
number is written on all the policies, for claim intimation
you can intimate the claim even while sitting at home,
after that you can go to the garage or you can
take it directly and you will get all the facilities from there,
if they do not provide the facility then
you can file the claim yourself from home also,
you just have to tell them
when your accident happened, how it happened, at what
time it happened by going to the toll free number  Where did it happen, they will
ask for all the details from you, they will ask for your driving license, they will
ask for its number and your
clarity mission will be lost, after that they will give you a
claim number, you can take that claim number and submit it
to the garage as well, if you are
not able to do anything then you can
go straight to the garage where all the facilities are
available and plus in this,
if it happens normally many times that
some people from outside do it, if
anyone is making a claim from a normal shop, if these
new facilities are not there then you can go
from home and lodge the claim and you can comfortably go to
any garage and get your car
repaired, in that no one will deny you that
this is not the case from here, sir your
claim will not be processed, if you have any All Over
India insurance then
you can go to any All Over India and make a claim,
no one can deny you for this, this is
your right, so any
policy, be it
New India, this or any All
India policy, there is a
processor in all of them  A toll free number is
given, you call on that toll free number
and tell them that I want to register a claim, to
register the claim you have to
follow whatever they tell you, your claim loss will be done accordingly,
if you need any other information
then you can ask me, you can comment, there is no
problem,
you can ask me any information by commenting,
thank you